Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ yogesharjunkumaar (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

FastAPI

Amazon ECS

Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD)

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Hindi (Limited Working)

Tamil (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

AMCAT Certified Data Processing Specialist

AMCAT Certified Business Analyst

AMCAT Certified Software Engineer

- IT Services

AMCAT Certified Software Engineer

- Product

AMCAT Certified Business Consultant

Publications

Health Monitoring Systems by Prognotive Computing using Big Data Analytics

Yogesh Arjun Kumaar

Machine Learning | AI | Software Engineering

Quincy, Massachusetts, United States

Summary

Graduate of Artificial Intelligence | Information technology Scientist. Machine learning enthusiast with competence in Full stack to Embedded system development. I consider myself a language agnostic programmer and lifelong student. Proud to have had an opportunity to be a leader, teacher and practitioner of Data and Computer Science. Have a special inclination towards building machines that learn from themselves and be a part of the social cog – making a difference.

Seasoned (7 years) in

Python ML stack (Pandas to Keras)

Computer Vision

Prompt Engineering

MLOps, Data Engineering

FastAPI, Spring boot

AWS ecosystem

GCP ecosystem

R language and R Shiny

React.js, Redux, Nginx, Flutter

Angularis, ASP Mvc, Sql Server, Jquery, D3. is

Angular Node.js Mongodb ExpressJs

Raspberry Pi, Arduino and embedded system engineering.

Experience

Harvard Business School

Information Technology Scientist - Digital, Data, and Design (D^3) Institute at Harvard

January 2023 - Present (4 months)

Cambridge, Massachusetts, United States

IoT Open Innovation Lab at Northeastern University

Research Assistant - Engineer

July 2021 - December 2022 (1 year 6 months)

Boston, Massachusetts, United States

IoT Open Innovation Lab at Northeastern University

Amazon Robotics

SDE

January 2022 - June 2022 (6 months)

Boston, Massachusetts, United States

KloudOne

Senior Software Engineer

October 2019 - November 2020 (1 year 2 months)

Chennai Area, India

Self employed

Software Engineer

January 2018 - October 2019 (1 year 10 months)

Chennai Area, India

Scientific Games

Associate Software Engineer

June 2016 - December 2017 (1 year 7 months)

Chennai

iNautix Technologies

Intern

February 2016 - May 2016 (4 months)

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

Education

Northeastern University

Master of Professional Studies, Enterprise Artificial Intelligence · (2021 - 2022)

Anna University

Bachelor of Technology (BTech), Information Technology (2012 - 2016)